The hunter becomes the hunted
The Frozen Ground is a thriller, crime film directed by Scott Walker.
An Alaska State Trooper partners with a young woman who escaped the clutches of
serial killer Robert Hansen to bring the murderer to justice.
Based on actual events.
Jack Halcombe, played by Nicolas Cage.
Cindy Paulson, played by Vanessa Hudgens.
Robert Hansen, played by John Cusack.
Allie Halcombe, played by Radha Mitchell.
Chelle Ringell, played by Jodi Lyn O'Keefe.
Fran Hansen, played by Katherine LaNasa.
The Frozen Ground is a 2013 American thriller film directed and written by Scott Walker, in his directorial debut,
starring Nicolas Cage, John Cusack, Vanessa Hudgens, Katherine LaNasa, Radha Mitchell, and 50 Cent.
Based on the crimes of the real-life Alaskan serial killer Robert Hansen, the film depicts an Alaskan State Trooper
seeking to apprehend Hansen by partnering with a young woman who escaped from Hansen's clutches.
The film was released in select theaters and directly to video on demand on
August 23, 2013, and received mixed reviews from critics.
Cage's performance was praised.
The film explores themes of prostitute, escape, hitman, winter, gun.
The tone is intense.